{"Topic": "Karnataka", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "In which year was Mysore renamed Karnataka?", "op1": "1972", "op2": "1973", "op3": "1971", "op4": "1975", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In terms of area Karnataka is the ____________ largest State in India?", "op1": "Fifth", "op2": "Sixth", "op3": "Seventh", "op4": "Eighth", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "At which place in Karnataka did Adi Shankaracharya establish the first of four mathas?", "op1": "Sringeri", "op2": "Gokarna", "op3": "Talakaveri", "op4": "Murdeshwar", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who of the following is the author of the State anthem of Karnataka \u2013 Jaya Bharata Jananiya Tanujate?", "op1": "Gopalakrishna Adiga", "op2": "Govindaray Nayak", "op3": "K Sivarama Karanth", "op4": "Kuvempu", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "On which of the following rivers are the Jog Falls (Gerosoppa Falls) situated?", "op1": "Sharavati", "op2": "Kaveri", "op3": "Ghataprabha", "op4": "Hemavathi", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the first person to be awarded the Jnanpith Award for Kannada?", "op1": "DR Bendre", "op2": "K Shivaram Karanth", "op3": "M Venkatasa Iyengar", "op4": "K Venkatappa Puttappa", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the State flower of Karnataka?", "op1": "Lotus", "op2": "Jasmine", "op3": "Marigold", "op4": "Rose", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Channapatna a place in Ramnagara district of Karnataka is famous for -", "op1": "Silk", "op2": "Sandalwood", "op3": "Toys", "op4": "Agarbatti", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following places is famous for metal handicraft known as Bidriware?", "op1": "Kalaburagi", "op2": "Belagavi", "op3": "Mysuru", "op4": "Bidar", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "At which place is the Suvarna Vidhana Soudha located?", "op1": "Dharwad", "op2": "Belagavi", "op3": "Mangalore", "op4": "Kalaburgi", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Ramdevarabetta Sanctuary has been notified in order to conserve -", "op1": "Vultures", "op2": "Sloth Bears", "op3": "Tigers", "op4": "Elephants", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following districts is rich in iron ore deposits?", "op1": "Kolar", "op2": "Vijayapura", "op3": "Ballari", "op4": "Kodagu", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The port Mangalore is located in which district of Karnataka?", "op1": "Udupi", "op2": "Dakshina Kannada", "op3": "Hassan", "op4": "Uttara Kannada", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "At which of the following places in Karnataka is a nuclear power plant located?", "op1": "Kaiga", "op2": "Karwar", "op3": "Kodagu", "op4": "Kakrapar", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "At which place is the historical monument Gol Gumbaz located?", "op1": "Bidar", "op2": "Vijayapura", "op3": "Kalburagi", "op4": "Belagavi", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who of the following is considered as the Father of Carnatic Music?", "op1": "Purandara Dasa", "op2": "Kanakadasa", "op3": "Basavanna", "op4": "Allam Prabhu", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "At which of the following places is a branch of Karnataka High Court located?", "op1": "Ballari", "op2": "Dharwad", "op3": "Bidar", "op4": "Mysuru", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The town of Shravanabelagola is an important pilgrimage centre for -", "op1": "Hindus", "op2": "Sikhs", "op3": "Muslims", "op4": "Jains", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In which year was Kannada granted the status of a classical language by the Central Govt?", "op1": "2006", "op2": "2007", "op3": "2008", "op4": "2009", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Where is India\u2019s only private sanctuary known as the SAI Sanctuary located?", "op1": "Kodagu", "op2": "Hubbali", "op3": "Bengaluru", "op4": "Mysuru", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In which city is the Central Institute of Indian Languages located?", "op1": "Mysuru", "op2": "Bengaluru", "op3": "Dharwad", "op4": "Udupi", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following is a National Film Award winning director as well as Jnanpith Award winning writer?", "op1": "SL Bhyrappa", "op2": "Girish Karnad", "op3": "BV Karanth", "op4": "Aravind Adiga", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who of the following is a recipient of literary award Saraswati Samman for his work in Kannada?", "op1": "Ramakrishna Hegde", "op2": "B.D. Jatti", "op3": "Sadananda Gowda", "op4": "Veerappa Moily", "Answer": 2}]}